Hi, this is John Stewart and this is how to find water in the case of an emergency.
Say you get stranded or lost, you’re going to want to find water.
Your body can go two to three weeks without food but your body cannot go longer that two to three days without water or some type of liquid but basically you really need water.
You want to find this fast and you want to try and find a large quantity of it.
First off water all ways flows down hill.
So if find a stream or something it'll normally lead to a bigger body of water.
That you can draw from if you do draw from a stream.
You want to find swift moving water that's filtered by a lot of rocks.
So try and find a rock bet a little rock waterfall.
That rocks and stuff they naturally filter the water.
To where it's not quite as dirty but it's still going to have some possible bacteria in it.
OK, so you don't want to drink from mud puddles.
You don't want to drink from saltwater.
This stuff really drain's you.
You might think it's water but the saltwater is going to help, not help at all.
It's too salty it takes and eats up more of the water that you have in your body.
OK, some of the things about water.
There's bacteria in water and so your water going to need to be treated.
OK, some people have filters, sanitizers and other things that's going to kill that bacteria.
OK, filtering water is not going to kill the bacteria.
So you got to treat the water other ways.
Easiest way to do this is to boil water.
You can boil water for five to ten minutes and it's going to kill any bacteria.
There might still be a piece of dirt or something in there but all your bad bacteria is going to be gone.
To where you can safely drink the water and let it help you out in the long run and that's how to find water in case you have to survive in nature.